Finding Aid for the Waldo Salt Papers, 1936-1987
UCLA Library, Performing Arts Special Collections
- UNPRODUCED FILMS
  - TULKU
    - Script Material
      - Master File, October 1983-May 1984. Script, incl. continuity notes and notes on characters (folder 1 of 2). (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Master File, October 1983-May 1984. Script, incl. continuity notes and notes on plot and characters, with dates and annotations (folder 2 of 2). (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Master File, June 1984-January 1985. Script, incl. continuity notes and notes on characters (folder 1 of 2). (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Master File, June 1984-January l985. Script, incl. continuity notes and notes on characters (folder 2 of 2). (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Script, 5/29/84. 112p + 4 unnumbered pages ("Final Sequence"). Note on cover: "Rough Rough". (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Script, August-September l984. 146p. (Missing several pages). (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Script, August-September l984. 137p. (Not the same as box 49, folder 5). (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Script, 2/28/85. 124p. (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - 39 index cards with notes on characters, situations, dialogue, settings, etc. (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Photocopy of "Tulku" (novel), by Peter Dickinson (l979, 286p). Passages of text marked by W.Salt. (Box 50, Folder 2)
- STAGE PRODUCTIONS
  - DAVY JONES' LOCKER
      - Script material for marionette play with music, produced by Bil and Cora Baird's Marionette Theatre. Incl: outline; play by W.Salt ("M.L.Davenport") and Arthur Burns; drafts and notes; musical score; programs. 11 items. (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - THE QUEEN AND THE BARON
      - Theatrical sketch, n.d., 15p. (See box 114, folder 12, for program of stage production of this sketch in Berkeley, l934). (Box 71, Folder 5)
      - Program of stage production of W.Salt's sketch "The Queen and the Baron", Berkeley, 1934; programs of two other stage productions in which W.Salt participated as actor and stage manager, 1936. 5 items. (Box 114, Folder 12)
  - SANDHOG
    - Clippings
      - Newspaper and magazine reviews of stage production at the Phoenix Theater, New York, November 1954. 14 items. (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - Photostats of theater reviews, 1954-55. 7 items. (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - "Sandhog" production in East Berlin. Incl: legal correspondence with German publisher, May-July 1959; German version of play, annotated, 134p; postcards and letters from Earl Robinson during trip to Eastern Europe, May-June 1959; etc. 22 items. (Box 90, Folder 8)
      - Congratulatory telegrams, 11/23/54. 15 items. (Box 90, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence regarding literary representation and theatrical rights for "Sandhog" in Europe, 1954-59. 12 items. (Box 90, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence with Earl Robinson regarding theatrical rights and royalties, and varios projects, 1961-71. 10 items. (Box 90, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, incl. congratulatory letters, 1954-76. 12 items. (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Financial-Legal
      - Contract between Earl Robinson/Waldo Salt and Cherry Lane Music, Inc., regarding rights for song "Johnny's Gone", 2/2/60. 4 copies. (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - Letters from the management of the Phoenix Theatre, incl. daily boxoffice ticket sales records for November-December 1954. (Box 90, Folder 11)
      - Legal correspondence regarding royalties and rights, 1960-77. 5 items. (Box 90, Folder 14)
      - Legal correspondence and hand-written notes concerning budget and estimates for New York production, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 16)
      - Legal correspondence regarding rights to Theodore Dreiser's short story; copyright of play; business partnership between W.Salt and Earl Robinson; etc, 1951-54. 44 items. (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Publicity Material
      - Programs for New York production, premiered 11/23/54 at the Phoenix Theatre; program for production by the Northwestern University Theatre, February-March, 1959. 4 items. (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Research Material
      - Hand-written research notes, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Newspaper clippings regarding construction of tunnel under the Hudson river. 4 items. (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Script Material
      - Typed and hand-written plot and scene outline, with notes, n.d. Uncollated. (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - Typed and hand-written notes and outlines, n.d. Uncollated. (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - Typed and hand-written script material, incl. rewrite notes, notes on Acts two and three, etc., n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Typed and hand-written script material, incl. notes and drafts, n.d. Uncollated. (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Typed and hand-written script material, incl: "First reading script: Acts one and two"; lyrics and score for various songs, with annotations. n.d. (Box 87, Folder 3)
      - Typed and hand-written drafts for Act one, Scenes one, four and five, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 4)
      - Typed and hand-written drafts for Act two, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 5)
      - Typed drafts for Act three, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 6)
      - Typed and hand-written rewrites for Acts one, two and three, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - Typed and hand-written material for "Cantata" show number, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 8)
      - Typed and hand-written notes and draft for "Kids" show number, incl. lyrics and score, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 9)
      - Carbon copies of Acts one, two and three (two different versions), n.d. (Box 87, Folder 10)
      - Uncollated script material, with annotations, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Uncollated script material, with annotations, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Uncollated script material, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Script, "First Draft", n.d. (Box 88, Folder 4)
      - Script, n.d. Note on cover: "Sandhog. A Play with Music by Waldo Salt and Earl Robinson, based upon "St. Columba and the River", a short story by Theodore Dreiser". (Box 88, Folder 5)
      - Script, n.d. (Another version of play). (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - Recording script and Chorus & Narration script, with annotations, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 7)
      - Script, annotated, n.d. Note on cover: "Sandhog. A Musical Play by Earl Robinson and Waldo Salt, based upon "St.Columba and the River", a short story by Theodore Dreiser. Property of Phoenix Theatre, by special arrangements with Rachel Productions". (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - Script, annotated, n.d. Label on cover: "Stage manager's book", incl. schedule of rehearsal and opening (November 9-23, l954), lists of cast and scene breakdown. (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Script, n.d. Note on cover: "Sandhog. A Folk Opera in 3 Acts, by Earl Robinson and Waldo Salt [..]. Directed by Howard Da Silva. Musical Direction by Ben Steinberg [..]. 3 copies. (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - Typed and hand-written script material, "First Rough", n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - Typed and hand-written lyrics for "Tunnel Dream" song, 9p; notebook with lyrics for "Sweat Song", n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - Sheet music for songs, published by Chappell and Co. Incl: "Twins" (6 copies); "Katie O'Sullivan" (8 copies); "Johnny-O" (5 copies); "The Bends" (4 copies). (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - Musical score for "Sandhog Quartet" (3 copies) and "Finale" (1 copy). (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - SIDE BY SIDE
      - Narration for musical performance (2 versions), annotated, n.d.; newspaper and magazine clippings, 1952-54. (Box 91, Folder 4)
- PROJECTS
  - ALL FOR ART
      - Comedy in one act, "(for women's clubs)", n.d., 20p. (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - ALTAR MASTERPIECE
      - Script and research material for project on XVth century Polish artist Wit Stwosz and his altar masterpiece for St.Mary's church in Cracow, n.d. Incl: shot breakdown with narration; and unnumbered typed and hand-written notes. (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - APPEARANCES
      - Theatrical sketch, n.d., 12p. (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - THE APPLE BLOSSOMS SPRING AND FALL
      - Story idea and drafts, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - AROUND THE WORLD
      - Story idea, "(Notes for a script)", n.d., 18p. (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - AU BORD DE LA SEINE
      - Theatrical sketch, "(a melodrama)", n.d., 9p. Manuscript signed by W.Salt. Sketches on back of some pages. (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - BABY GIRL EMILY CAHILL
      - Story idea, script material and scene breakdown, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - BANK ACCOUNT, BIG BLUE BUICK AND BERTHA
      - Story idea, with notes, n.d., 4p. (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - THE BIG SHOT
      - Treatment, 3/3/50, 21p, for Norma Productions, Burbank, California. Final draft screenplay, 5/31/50, 43p. (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - BLAST OF SILENCE
    - Notebook
      - Notebook containing notes, sketches and drawings for project, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - BLIND LOVE
      - Story idea, n.d., 15p; hand-written notes. (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - BOLIVAR
      - Treatment, 7/12/63, 80p. (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - CAPTAIN KIDD
      - Correspondence and script material regarding pirate film with Ben Hecht. Incl: two different treatments of story, n.d. (one,108p, with annotations); letters and telegrams to and from W.Salt ("Mel Davenport"), B.Hecht and R.Haggiag, 1959-60 (9 items). (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - COLONEL MARCH OF SCOTLAND YARD (TV series, 1957)
      - Scripts for British TV series: "The Case of the Kidnapped Poodle", 2 versions with introductory and rewrite notes, n.d.; "The Abominable Showman", ("Script No.7"), n.d., annotated; drafts and notes. Production and air dates not verified. (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - COME AWAY HOME
      - Story outline, n.d., 17p. (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - A COMEDY OF BAD MANNERS
      - Theatrical sketch, n.d., 7p. (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - CORONET BLUE (TV series)
      - Script material for Plautus Productions, Inc.: Outline: "Warrior of the Empty Hand", n.d., 20p; annotated script, same title, n.d.; annotated script: "Tomoyo", 5/20/65; script and research material related to series, 1965. Air date not verified. (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - THE CRIMSON PIRATE
      - Script material: Treatment by W.Salt, 11/22/50, for Norma Productions, with some annotations, 53p; script, "English Estimating", no author, 3/7/51, 148p; script, "Revised Final for England", by Roland Kibbee, 9/6/51, 115p. (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Story idea, drafts, typed and hand-written research notes. n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - CRISIS IN CANDY
      - Story idea, n.d., 7p. 3 copies. (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - DANGEROUS THING
      - Story idea, n.d., 12p; typed and hand-written notes. (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - DESIGN FOR PRIVATE CONVERSATION
      - Theatrical sketch, n.d., 9p, with program insert from the Palo Alto Community Players, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - DIANA
      - Story idea, n.d., 14p; hand-written notes. (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - THE DOCTOR OF DOOM
      - Nine sketches for radio program, n.d., annotated. (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - THE EARTH-OUR PLANET
      - Script and research material for project on Earth and astronomer N.Copernicus' anniversary, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - THE END
      - Theatrical sketch, "(An Episode of Melodrama)", n.d., 10p. (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - END OF SUMMER
      - Lyrics. Typed script, n.d., 3p (3 copies); typed and hand-written drafts; small notebook with lyrics, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - FILMSTRIP FOR PENNSYLVANIA RAILROAD
      - Treatment and notes for educational project promoting use of railroads, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - THE FIRESIDE FAMILY
      - Script material for TV series project on traditional American songs, n.d. Incl: outlines for series and various episodes; 2 versions of script: "Whistle, Daughter, Whistle", 10 and 20p; hand-written notes. (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - THE FIRST WEEK
      - Theatrical sketch, n.d., hand-written in 3 Stanford University blue books. (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - FLAT-OUT!
      - Story idea for a TV series, n.d. Typed script, 3p. Clipping with story by Tom Wolfe, in "Esquire", n.d., 14p. (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - FREEDOM ROAD
      - Script by Howard Fast and Leo Hurwitz, n.d., 216p. (Box 64, Folder 9)
      - Script material: script, n.d., with note on cover: "What's left of old script", 229p (missing pages 1-7); scene-sequence breakdown, 79p. (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Photocopy of letter to Joseph Gould concerning story outline, 4/1/47. (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - FRONTIER LAWYER
      - Outline for TV series project, n.d., 6p. (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Notes and sketches for TV project, incl. drawings, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - GALLANT LADY
      - Story treatment, 33p; scene breakdown (two versions: 11 and 12p); hand-written and typed notes regarding characters and plot. n.d. (Box 120, Folder 7)
  - GOOD GIRLS
      - Two versions of story idea, May 1983, 10 and 12p; typed notes. (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - GOOD MORNING!
      - Two versions of play, "(An American Bathroom Farce in 3 acts)", n.d. One is complete (76p) and annotated, the other has act II and III only. (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - THE GUIDE
      - Story idea, n.d., 2p. (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - HEY, RUBE!
      - Outline for TV series, n.d., 9p, using pseudonym M.L.Davenport. Annotated. (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - THE HIGHWAYMAN (TV series)
      - Script material British TV series, 1958: scripts for episodes #1 and #2, n.d., 35 and 35p; outlines for #3 and episodes titled:"The Indiscreet Time-piece" and "The Distiller's Apprentice"; research notes; series outline. Production date not verified. (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence with producers (Sapphire Films Ltd.) regarding scripts for TV series project, 1956-58. (Box 80, Folder 47)
      - Script for episode #3: "The Duel", n.d. 35p. Another title for the series, on front page: "Stand and Deliver!". (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - IF AT FIRST ..
      - Theatrical sketch, n.d., 15p. (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - IN HOUSES I ENTER
      - Script material for television play by Arthur Behrstock (pseudonym for W.Salt). Incl: Outline; scene breakdown; script, 10/24/55-11/1/55 ("incomplete"), 31p; hand-written notes. (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - INDEMNITY
      - Script material: outline for TV series, n.d., 4p; annotated scripts for three episodes -one dated 1957- by Milton Gelman [possibly pseudonym for W.Salt?]; hand-written notes and newspaper clipping. (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - INDIAN SUMMER
      - Story idea, n.d., 1p. (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - THE INGRATE
      - Theatrical sketch, n.d., 10p. (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - INSURRECTION AT CHAPARRAL
      - Story idea, n.d., 4p; longer version of story, hand-written in two notebooks, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - KARL TANZLER-COUNT VON COSEL
      - Research material on Karl Tanzler, a.k.a. Count Von Cosel. Incl: newspaper clippings, n.d.; photocopies of newspaper articles and typed articles. (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - LAST CELEBRATION
      - Typed and hand-written notes and drafts on film project about the end of World War II; two letters from W.Salt concerning project, dated April 21 and 23, 1963. (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - THE LEGEND OF SLEEPY HOLLOW
      - Script material: scene-sequence breakdown, n.d.; script, 2/24/45, 122p, 2 copies: one with revised blue pages. (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - LIFE IS FOR THE BIRDS
      - Hand-written and typed notes for film project; letter from Elektra Productions regarding film, 6/17/57; 3 newspaper clippings from The New York Times, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - LOVE AND THE LITTLE FANS
      - Story idea by Arthur Behrstock (pseudonym for W.Salt), n.d., 8p, 2 copies. (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - MACGOWAN
      - Play in three acts, n.d., hand-written in 9 Stanford University blue books; scenes "1" through "5" in separate pages. (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - A MAN NAMED THIN
      - Outline for TV series project on Dashiell Hammett stories, n.d., 9p; photocopy of "A Man Named Thin" (short story) by D.Hammett. (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - THE MARK OF ROMULUS
      - Outline and notes on characters and plot for TV series project on ancient Rome, n.d, 6p; 55 hand-drawn cartoon strips by M.Wong and J.P.Cahn. (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - A MATTER OF CONVICTION
      - Script, with shot breakdown, for Harold Hecht Productions, n.d. 157p. Annotations on last two pages. (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - MERMAID IN MANHATTAN
      - Story idea and draft, 3/2/36, 16p. (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - MIGRANT WORKERS
      - Research material on migrant workers. Incl: photocopies of newspapers and magazine articles; photocopy of book "The Offshores", 1966; copy of report on migrant workers' situation, l940. (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Research material on migrant workers. Incl.: photographs; photocopies of newspaper clippings; legislation; booklets and pamphlets; tape transcripts of interviews with workers, 1940 and various other dates. (Box 79, Folder -)
  - MISCELLANEOUS PROJECTS
      - Unidentified story materials: typed and hand-written, drafts and notes, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - MOTHER
      - Monologue, n.d., 3p. (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - MR. BROADWAY
      - Script material: story idea, n.d., 3p; outline, n.d., 5p; outline: "Shake Hands with Billy Shine", n.d., 17p; script, n.d., 66p; letter from CBS Television rejecting W.Salt's story for "Mike Bell" series, 8/31/64. (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - MR.BROADWAY
    - Notebook
      - Notebook containing notes, sketches and drawings for "Mr.Broadway" project, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - THE NIGHT OF THE BERSERK TURK
      - Script materials for television project: two versions of treatment, n.d., 11 and 13p, with annotations; script, n.d., various pagings. (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - NO MORE TONIGHT
      - Theatrical play, "(A Comedy in Three Acts)", 1936, no paging. In collaboration with Robert R. Presnell, Jr. (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - NOSES FOR NEWS
      - Sketch for radio program, 12/3/35, 11p. (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - THE OCTOPUS
      - Correspondence between W.Salt ("Mel Davenport") and producer Sydney Harmon regarding possible adaptation of novel "The Octopus", July-September 1960. 4 items. (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - OPEN SEASON
      - Theatrical play, n.d., various pagings. Note on cover: "Property of Sidney Harmon". 6 copies -slightly different-, marked "1"-"5", with annotations and corrections. (folder 1 of 3). (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - Theatrical play, n.d., various pagings. Note on cover: "Property of Sidney Harmon". 6 copies -slightly different-, marked "1"-"5", with annotations and corrections. (folder 2 of 3). (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Theatrical play, n.d., various pagings. Note on cover: "Property of Sidney Harmon". 6 copies -slightly different-, marked "1"-"5", with annotations and corrections. (folder 3 of 3). (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - OPERATION LIFE
      - Treatment for a documentary film, n.d., 5p. (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - THE ORIGINAL MANNER
      - Outline and drafts for film project based on life of Henry Rousseau, "Le Douanier", 7/15/59, with annotations; letter to "Z" about project, undated. (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - PEACE
      - Two versions of theatrical sketch, with different titles: "Peace", n.d., 7p; "Ten More Minutes", n.d., 6p; hand-written draft, n.d., 6p. (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Script materials for documentary project: shot breakdown in 6 reels, n.d., 29p, annotated; copy of song; typed notes by Joris Ivens, "The World Peace Congress Film", n.d., 2p. (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - THE PENALTY
      - Theatrical sketch, n.d., 9p. (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - PENNYWORTH
      - Uncollated pages of play in three acts, with annotations and corrections, n.d.; hand-written notes in two Stanford blue books, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - POTENTATE
      - Notebook containing notes, sketches and drawings for project, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - THE PRESS AGENT
      - Theatrical sketch, n.d., 9p. Annotated. (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - THE PRINCESS AND THE KING
      - Theatrical sketch, "(A Caprice)", n.d., 17p. (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - PROXY
      - Theatrical play, "(A Comedy in Three Acts)", n.d., various pagings, with annotations and numerous pages with revisions. In collaboration with William Salt. (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - RED BONE WOMAN
      - Scene outline, n.d., 6p. (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - REFORM TICKET
      - Story idea, n.d., 6p. (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - THE REPORTER (TV series)
      - Outlines of two episodes for CBS 1964 TV series: "The Doormouse", 4/19/64, 17p, 2 copies, annotated; "A Hotel with a Heart", n.d., 6p, 3 copies, annotated; character outline, no author, n.d. Production dates not verified. (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - ROSENBERG-SOBELL
      - Outline for film project about the Rosenberg-Sobell case, n.d., 89p; letter, signed "Milt", concerning W.Salt's outline, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - SAN FRANCISCO-1945
      - Outline for project on San Francisco and the creation of the United Nations in 1945, n.d., 12p. (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - THE SCENE TONIGHT
      - Script material for TV series project: 3 versions of outline; outline, script and drafts for episode #1:"A Screaming Silence", by Mel Davenport (pseudonym), n.d., 27 and 57p; correspondence with H.Brodkin (Plautus Productions), Feb.1963-April 1964. (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - SIXTY MILLION JOBS
      - Treatment, n.d., 17p. (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - SONG OF SONGS
      - Hand-written notes on King Solomon's poem, 5p; research notes in notebook, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - THE SPICE OF LIFE
      - Script for TV project for Norma Productions, 6/1/50, 48p. In collaboration with Frank Tashlin. (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - STAKEOUT (TV series)
      - Scripts by M.L.Davenport (pseudonym) for Screen Gems, Inc: "Scared Witness", 11/28/58, 40p; "The Gasparilla", 1/26/59, 39p; "Trial and Error", 3 /11/59, 36p; "Danger Road", 3/26/59, 42p; "The Fugitive", 4/26/59, 39p. (Box 74, Folder 2)
      - Script materials: outlines for various episodes, n.d.; 14 memos from the Florida Sheriff's Bureau, December 1958-April 1959; research notes, 2 items; production materials, April 1959, 3 items. (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - Script materials: outline and notes for episode "The Kale Boys", l958; various versions of script and drafts: story by M.L.Davenport and scripts by Will Lorin, 7/15/58 and 11/2/58, and by Kenneth Gamet, 12/10/58. (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - THEY GO SOUTH FOR THE WINTER
      - Theatrical sketch ("A Farce"). Typed script, n.d. 8p. (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - THOSE CASEY KIDS
      - Screen treatment by M.L.Davenport (pseudonym for W.Salt), n.d. 105p. (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - TIME BOMB
      - Story idea, n.d. 1p. (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - THE TOWER OF BABEL JOB
      - Script material for musical play. Incl: typed script, with annotations, corrections and rewrite notes, n.d., 14p; music sheets with lyrics; manuscript of play in small notebook; letter to W.Salt from Earl Robinson, n.d.; uncollated script materials. (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - TWO MEALS ON SUNDAY
      - Theatrical play, l936. Various pagings. (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - VANISHED YESTERDAY
      - Theatrical sketch ("A Farce"), n.d. 9p. (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - VOYAGE OF "THE BEAGLE"
      - Correspondence with Sapphire Films Ltd. (Great Britain) regarding film project on Charles Darwin's voyage, June-July 1958 (3 letters); research notes, April 1963, 6p. (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - WARZAWA
      - Scene outline for documentary project on Warsaw. Two versions (21 and 22p), annotated, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 11)
  - THE WAY WEST
      - Script, 3/16/64. 84p. Incl. script notes, l963. (Box 118, Folder 12)
  - WHO KILLED SERGE RUBINSTEIN?
      - Magazines: "Reader's Digest", June 1956; "Newsweek", 2/14/55; "Business Week", 2/5/55; "Fortune", May 1955; "Life", 2/7/55. (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Notes and sketches for "Who Killed Serge Rubinstein?" and other projects, incl. drawings, n.d. (List on front page). (Box 110, Folder 6)
      - Script, "draft 3", by M.L.Davenport (pseudonym). 150p. (2 copies). (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Script Material
      - Outline and scene breakdown (typed and hand-written versions), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 13)
      - Uncollated script materials, incl. notes on characters and plot, outlines, etc. n.d. (Box 118, Folder 14)
  - WISHING WELL/ 15 WORDS